Kelvin Samuel Klutse

I.T support Specialist | Ux/Ui designer | Website designer

Address: Nii Kaklaku Gbokle Street Baatsona Spintex, Accra

Phone: 233202950603 | 233546105100

Email: Vankelvin603@gmail.com Portfolio: van.nextlinegh.com

ABOUT

I am Kelvin Samuel Klutse (Van Kelvin). An Accra based Website developer, Ux/Ui designer, Brand identity designer and social media manager.

I'm most passionate about building new websites every day and always learning new things. As a designer and developer, I understand the optimal user interface should look excellent and operate even better. Alongside my clients, I find problems and solve them. To put it another way, I build more daring online experiences.

I am creative, very reliable and consistent about what I do.

My job for the past 4 years has been to help organizations and individuals create compelling, simple but creative designs that boost their brands. This includes Brand Identity Design, Product Design, and Books and Stationeries' Design, logos, flyers, social media post that can be use and love by millions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Accra Institute of Technology: 2017/08-2022/08

Diploma: Information Technology Waec: General Arts

Accra Institute of Technology: 2016/08-2017/08 Dodi Papase senior High Technical School: 2008/09-2012/05

Address: Nii Kaklaku Gbokle Street Baatsona Spintex, Accra

Phone: 233202950603 | 233546105100

Email: <u>Vankelvin603@gmail.com</u> Portfolio: <u>van.nextlinegh.com</u>

WORK HISTORY

I.T support Officer

ShaQ Express, Accra Ghana: 07/21-12/21

- Monitor and maintain computer systems and networks.
- Troubleshoot system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults.
- Set up new users' accounts and profiles and deal with password issues.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners.
- Conduct consistent network backup operations.
- Providing technical support across the company.

Website Designer

ShaQ Express, Accra Ghana: 07/21-12/21

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, Css, Laravel and JavaScript coding.
- Illustrated page design concepts by blending arrangement, style and aesthetic elements to meet predetermined preferences.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software.
- Collaborated with marketing department to determine organizational need and design pages to meet goals.
- Implemented Google-based SEO and ad campaigns to meet budget specifications.
- Applied latest emerging technology, software and project application trends to update and maintain site applicability.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Determined coding requirements for site creation, including e-commerce capability, security and specialized scripts.

Social Media Manager

Euro Decor Ghana: 02/2020-08/2020

At Euro décor Ghana I developed marketing content such as blogs, promotional materials and advertisements for social media. Analysed and reported social media and online marketing campaign results. Identified target market and key segments through in-depth analysis of markets and related trends. Promoted successful outcome of web development strategy by aligning consistent brand messaging and visual designs across

Address: Nii Kaklaku Gbokle Street Baatsona Spintex, Accra

Phone: 233202950603 | 233546105100

Email: Vankelvin603@gmail.com Portfolio: van.nextlinegh.com

all digital outlets. Increased customer engagement through social media. I was the team head for the successful development and hosting of Eurohomeshotel.com a subsidiary of Euro Décor Ghana.

I.T support Officer

Global fx Institute: 07/2019-02/2020

I provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.

I collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems. Installed security applications and devices and suggested additional security measures. Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data. I Identified and solved technical issues using variety of diagnostic tools and tactics.

I provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.

I collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems. Installed security applications and devices and suggested additional security measures. Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data. I Identified and solved technical issues using variety of diagnostic tools and tactics.

Brand identity designer

Freelancer, Accra Ghana: 2017-date

- Created aesthetically-pleasing advertisements that complemented products.
- Developed creative design for marketing packages, including print materials, brochures, banners and signs.
- Used Photoshop and adobe illustrator to develop product mockups and prototype designs.
- Met with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.
- Contributed design ideas in early planning stages with customers and project managers.
- Developed collateral such as display, marketing and packaging materials to support product branding strategies.

Ui/UX Designer

Freelancer, Accra Ghana: 2019-date

- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Collaborated with teammates to deliver valuable features meeting business and customer needs.
- Evaluated user research to convert abstract ideas and requirements into planning tools such as journey maps, user personas and storyboards.

Address: Nii Kaklaku Gbokle Street Baatsona Spintex, Accra

Phone: 233202950603 | 233546105100

Email: Vankelvin603@gmail.com Portfolio: van.nextlinegh.com

- Devised site maps, user flows, wireframes and mockups for designs based on proven methodologies, stakeholder requests and end-user feedback.
- Employed End-to-End Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) methodologies during multiple projects, streamlining cross-discipline development and producing results
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- User Interface (UI) design
- Application support
- Technical support
- Agile development methodologies
- Technical issues analysis
- Desktop support
- Advertising understanding
- Branding Strategies
- Graphic and Logo designing
- Visuals and digitals designs

SOFT SKILLS

- Curious
- Reliable
- Consistent
- Communicator
- Flexible
- Self-Learner
- Enthusiastic
- Analytical
- Self-Motivation

SOFTWARE & PROG

- Adobe Xd
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- After effect
- WordPress
- Visual studio and code
- Microsoft Office suit
- Java
- Html & Css
- C++
- MySQL

INTERESTS

Music (I love country music, soul music's, Hip hop and RnB and not forgetting my hometown local music Agbadza

Movie

Filming & Acting

LANGUAGES

- Ewe
- English
- Twi

Address: Nii Kaklaku Gbokle Street Baatsona Spintex, Accra

Phone: 233202950603 | 233546105100

Email: <u>Vankelvin603@gmail.com</u> Portfolio: <u>van.nextlinegh.com</u>